<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<eposap:Epos xmlns:eposap="http://www.epos-ip.org/terms.html" xmlns:adms="http://www.w3.org/ns/adms#" xmlns:cnt="http://www.w3.org/2008/content#" xmlns:dcat="http://www.w3.org/ns/dcat#" xmlns:dct="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/" xmlns:http="http://www.w3.org/2006/http#" xmlns:locn="http://www.w3.org/ns/locn#" xmlns:owl="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:schema="http://schema.org/" xmlns:skos="http://www.w3.org/2004/02/skos/core#" xmlns:vcard="http://www.w3.org/2006/vcard/ns#" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.epos-ip.org/terms.html https://raw.githubusercontent.com/epos-eu/EPOS-DCAT-AP/master/schemas/EPOS-DCAT-AP.xsd">
   <eposap:Project>
      <dct:title xml:lang="en">EPOS Implementation Phase (EPOS IP)</dct:title>
      <dct:description xml:lang="en">The nations of Europe are distributed around some of the most complex and dynamic geological systems on the planet and understanding these is essential to the security of livelihoods and economic power of Europeans. Many of the solutions to the grand challenges in the geosciences have been led by European scientists – the understanding of stratigraphy (the timing and distribution of layers of sediment on Earth) and the discovery of the concept of plate tectonics being among the most significant. Our ability to monitor the Earth is rapidly evolving through development of new sensor technology, both on- and below-ground and from outer space; we are able to deliver this information with increasing rapidity, integrate it, provide solutions to geological understanding and furnish essential information for decision makers. Earth science monitoring systems are distributed across Europe and the globe and measure the physico-chemical characteristics of the planet under different geological regimes. EPOS will bring together 24 European nations and combine national Earth science facilities, the associated data and models together with the scientific expertise into one integrated delivery system for the solid Earth. This infrastructure will allow the Earth sciences to achieve a step change in our understanding of the planet; it will enable us to prepare for geo-hazards and to responsibly manage the subsurface for infrastructure development, waste storage and the use of Earth’s resources. With a European Research Infrastructure Consortium (ERIC) to be located in Rome (Italy), EPOS will provide an opportunity for Europe to maintain world-leading European Earth sciences and will represent a model for pan-European federated infrastructure.</dct:description>
   </eposap:Project>
</eposap:Epos>
